Nikos Kousiadis

Data Scientist

Galatsi, 11147, Greece
₩ 8th December 1990
(+30) 6945 382 564
nkousiadis@hotmail.com
in Link, Link
Military service obligations fulfilled

About me

Data science professional with demonstrated abilities in manipulating and analyzing data to solve problems, building creative visualizations to gain insights and developing machine learning models to predict business outcomes. Solid skills in mathematics and programming and experience with a variety of relational databases and big data systems. Keen interest in R programming for data science and development of data products with R Shiny to automate analytics processes and present findings.

Work Experience

Data Scientist - Principle Analyst, Media Centre of Excellence, IRI ACE, Athens	Tools
02/2019 - Present	Hadoop Hive
Product development and big data analysis on Hadoop Hive	R
Combine and analyze multiple data sources of media campaign exposure, point-of-sale, frequent	Unix
shopper and causal data to get deeper insights of actual in-store sales lift impact of ad spend	Julia
 Monitor, evaluate and optimize code quality and speed 	Jira
Responsible for the maintenance, development and team support of various products	
Data Analyst, Analytics Department, Intelen Inc, Athens	
05/2017 - Present	Tools
,	R
 Design, develop and maintain analytics app (R Shiny) for the following purposes: data visualisation, statistical results, simulation, KPI monitoring, customer scoring and segmentation, predictive modelling, etc. 	PostgreSQL
	MySQL
• Use supervised and unsupervised machine learning methods to optimize customer experience,	R Shiny
revenue generation and other business outcomes	R Markdown
Enhance customer experience building recommender systems for personalized services	git
Define, measure, monitor KPIs and design new data-driven business products	MS Excel
Data Scientist, Credit Risk Department, ICAP Group, Athens	Tools
07/2016 - 05/2017	Tools
,	R
 Prepare the thesis "Storage of Default Characterization Data", as part of the M.Sc. in Business Analytics, Athens University of Economics and Business 	SAS Base
• Support regulatory requirements on reporting and monitoring of ICAP's credit assessment	SQL
evolution data to regulators	Jira
 Support reporting to European Rating Platform (ERP/RADAR), the platform maintained by ESMA on credit rating agencies data 	MS Excel
 Design, develop and maintain statistical procedures and tools (automated and semi-automated procedures) for the monitoring of credit assessment evolution in SAS and R softwares, as well as, 	

data management and automation activities

Education

M.Sc. in Business Analytics, Athens University of Economics and Business	
Degree with Distinction, 8.86 / 10	ı
10/2015 - 01/2017	
Field Study Project (Master Thesis) conducted in ICAP Group:	

Field Study Project (Master Thesis) conducted in ICAP Group:

Development of automated system in R for the following activities on default characterization data:

- Data cleansing, exploration and transformation
- Statistical reporting and visualization
- Creation of historical database and integration in optimised data schema

Part of master projects:

- Data warehousing, Data management, ETL
- Statistical analyses implementing various methods, e.g. regression, classification, clustering, LASSO, PCA, Naïve Bayes, etc.
- Application development using big data tools
- Data Mining, Large Scale Optimization, Visual Analytics, Recommender Systems, Business Analysis

B.Sc. in Mathematics, University of Athens

10/2008 - 09/2013

• Main topics of interest: Probability Theory, Operations Research, Stochastics, Statistics

Tools

Tools MySQL, MemSQL Hadoop, Spark Redis, Mongo DB

Neo4i

R, Python

Java, Scala

Pentaho

Rapid Miner

SAS Miner

Spotfire

IBM Watson

R, Java

MATLAB

Languages

• English: Perfect knowledge, Proficiency of Michigan, 2011

• French: Good knowledge, Paris - Sorbonne B2, 2014

Professional development

e-learning courses: Coursera, edX, Datacamp

02/2015 - Present

Enhanced my programming skills and broadened my knowledge gaining hands-on experience and better understanding in several subjects and tools of data science and analytics. Full list of certifications in https://www.nikoskousiadis.com

Additional info

06/2015: GMAT: Score 700